Guide to the Alison Jolly papers, circa 1919-2014
Jolly, Alison papers
- Series III. Notes and Papers
  - General Documents
    - Berenty Troops 2007 Location: Berenty, 2007; typed report (Box 13, Folder 12)
      General characteristics
    - Berenty notes Location: Berenty, notes (Box 13, Folder 12)
      Troop A1, A2, A3 Matrilines, Tracy Dubovick
    - Day range master maps Location: Berenty, maps (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Blumenfeld Jones (Kathryn Dainis) Location: Berenty, 1972-73; data with maps (Box 13, Folder 14)
      original 1972-73 vegetation data, with maps
    - Flag Trees Location: Berenty, 1992; notes and data (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Flag Trees Location: Berenty, 1993; notes and data (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Flag Trees Location: Berenty, 1991; notes and data (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Princeton population talk Location: Berenty, 1993; notes and slides (Box 14, Folder 1)
      Veg survey by Susan Pinkus, 1993, graphics by RBJ
    - George Williams Map Location: Berenty, map and notes (Box 14, Folder 1)
      Can be transferred to Arc view
    - Lemur catta ID template Location: Berenty, template (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Range Data Location: Berenty, 1995; data with maps (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Master set of maps Location: Berenty, maps (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Madagascar stamps Location: Berenty, envelope and stamps (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Day ranges Location: Berenty, Sept 1995, Sept 1999, Oct 2005; notes and data (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Berenty Notebook Author: Alison Jolly Berenty, 2007; notebook (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Condition Study Location: Berenty, 2004; notes and data (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Tamarind growth Location: Berenty, 2004; notes and data (Box 14, Folder 2)
      Kathryn Blumenfeld-Jones and Anne Mertl Millhollen
    - Tamarind Locations Location: Berenty, 2007; maps and data (Box 14, Folder 2)
      George williams GPS - not very accurate!
    - Alison Jolly report to J de Heaulme Author: Alison Jolly Berenty, 2005; report (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Range Maps Location: Berenty, 1999-2005; maps (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - National Geographic Soc report on Leucaena leucocephla and bald lemurs Author: Graham Crawford Berenty, 2003-2006; report (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Major Tree sample Location: Berenty, 1998-1999; data list (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Water depth and renewal in well Author: Anne Mertl Millhollen Location: Berenty, 2002; notes (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Millhollen report to J de Heaulme Author: Anne Mertl Millhollen Location: Berenty, 2002; report (Box 14, Folder 3)
      Early baffled attempts to locate and understand bald lemur syndrome
    - 2002 Census Location: Berenty, 2002; data (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Photo IDS Crawford bald lemur/leucaena study Author: Colin Radford Location: Berenty, 2003; photos and cds in files (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Berenty veg data summary, 1972-2000 Author: Blumenfeld Jones Location: Berenty, 2003; data summary (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Koyama/Soma tamarind map Location: Berenty, 2003; map (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Bald lemur tourist notice Location: Berenty, 2003; note (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - DIA IDS and Range Location: Berenty, 2003; data (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - List of papers which should have been written Location: Berenty, 2003; list of papers (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Initiation and leading of travel in wild troop of Lemur catta Author: Wendy Miles and Haja Rambeloarivony Berenty, 2003; paper (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Earthwatch check sheets and instructions Location: Berenty, 2003; list of instructions (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Predators: 2003 Location: Berenty, 2003; notes (Box 14, Folder 5)
      two Buteos eating juvenile Lemur catta. Not clear if killed or scavenging.
    - Bald lemur hypotheses Location: Berenty, 2003; notes (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Draft paper on fur condition and bald lemur syndrome Location: Berenty, 2003; paper (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Social structure and social correlates of hair loss in a troop of ring-tailed lemurs at Berenty Author: Alison Tew Location: Berenty, 2003; thesis (Box 14, Folder 5)
      Msc thesis Oxford Brookes, bald lemur syndrome in troop C1
    - Population health evaluation of ringtailed lemurs (Lemur catta) Berenty Reserve Author: Crawford and Ostapak Berenty, 2005; paper (Box 14, Folder 5)
      bald lemur syndrome
    - Berenty vet project Location: Berenty, 2002-2003; letters and proposal (Box 14, Folder 5)
      bald lemurs
    - Berenty tree list and Tamarind maps Location: Berenty, 1998-99; lists and maps (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Lemur catta database, Berenty reserve, Mad. Author: Alison Jolly and Francine Dolins Location: Berenty, 2006; proposal (Box 14, Folder 6)
      proposal for Berenty database to American museum of Natural History - agreed in principle by Ian Tattershall, but would have needed salaried database person to prepare data.
    - Conservation of two sympatric lemurs species Lemurcatta and Eulemur collaris in forest fragments Author: Josia Razafindramanana Location: Berenty, 2008; thesis proposal and recommendation (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Berenty troop ranges - Eulemur - 1994, L. Catta 1995 Location: Berenty, 1994-5; troop data (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - List of 365 Lemur catta Location: Berenty, 1990-2003; list (Box 14, Folder 6)
      full day follows plus 79 E. fuvus follows and 45 P. verreauxi follows
    - Spatial defense in lemur catta at different population densities in Berenty Author: AJ, J.C. Cline, M.A. Braun, C.N. Mills, T. Dubovick, Hee-joo N. Park, C.B. Hicks Location: Berenty, 1997 (data 1995); draft paper (Box 14, Folder 6)
      draft paper on territorality
    - Territorality Location: Berenty, 1995; notes (Box 14, Folder 6)
      Kathryn Blumenthal-jones rethink of her 1972-73 scrub troop comments on spatial defense paper
    - Spatial defense and territoriality paper Location: Berenty, 1995/1997; reviews and comments (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Maps of range, scent, feeding and encounters won/lost by quadrat Location: Berenty, 1995; maps (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Francine Dolins work for IPS 1998 Location: Berenty, 1996-7; data (Box 14, Folder 6)
      power point on spatial defense
    - Questionnaires for scientists on reading habits when they were children (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - MGB letters Location: various, 1893-1977; letters (Box 14, Folder 8-9)
      3 page version, later cut to "I think I have been here before"
    - letter from Morris (Billy) to daughter Joan Gilbert Martin and Joan Gilbert to Alison Jolly, 1963 and 2003; letters (Box 14, Folder 10)
      family news including MGB and AMK trip to Mad., AB and RJ fiancailles.
    - Camille Paglia request for "The Witch of East 72nd Street Author: Allison Zimmer Location:, 17-Jan-96; letter (Box 14, Folder 10)
      probably to annoy "serious" poets
    - MGB "Dear, dead dumbshow Author: MGB, poem (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - letter from Alison Jolly to Christine Agostino 903 Wyckoff Road Author: Alison Jolly Location:, 2000; letters (Box 14, Folder 10)
      french video on Nabokov - interview with Alison Jolly shot in 903
    - The Morris and Alison Bishop Collection of Vladimir Nabokov, 1999; catalogue with envelope (Box 14, Folder 10)
      Vladimir Nabokov sent a copy of every first edition to MGB and AMK, both as literary and professional friendship and knowing they would be an investment. Sold by Alison Jolly through Dimitri Ns bookseller, Glen Horowitz. Many bought by Cornell Library.
    - letter to Alison Jolly from Hunter R. Rawlings, Cornell, 13-Oct-95; letter (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - letter to Alison Jolly from Bernhard Kendler, Cornell University Press, 17-Jan-96; letter (Box 14, Folder 11)
      MGB: 'I think I have been here before'
    - AMKB envelope 'Addresses', envelope with cuttings (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - I think I have been here before' Author: MGB Location:, typed manuscript (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Morris Bishop tells it like it was' Author: MGB Location:, 1971; news article (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Research and Reward' Author: MGB, Mar-65; news article (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - I think I have been here before' Author: MGB Location:, 1981; bound manuscript (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - typescript by Anna Wilson from original selection by Alison Jolly, box tied with string (Box 14, Folder 12-14)
      The xerox copy was cut up by AMKB for the condensed version.
    - letter re: "Taught to Kill a Farm Boy" Author: Michael Fisher Location:, 2000; letter (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Margaret Clulow, c. 2000; Letters and documents (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Observed L. catta ranging to March 12 1963 Author: Alison Jolly Location: Berenty, 12-Mar-63; map (Box 14, Folder 16)
      Troop 1, my main study group became Troop D, in same range and Troop 2 became Troop C. see Jolly and Pride 1999 on range inertia
    - road map of Madagascar Location: Madagascar, 1960; map (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Librarie Ambozontary Location: Madagascar, 1963; catalogue (Box 14, Folder 16)
      catalogue of books in Malagasy for primary and secondary schools
    - Berenty field Notebooks Author: Alison Jolly Berenty, 1963; small notebooks (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - 1: 100,000 map of Nosy Be Location: Nosy Be, 1958; map (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - 1: 100,000 map of Amboasary Sud and sisal plantations Location: Amboasary Sud, 1957; map (Box 14, Folder 16)
      My house and de Heaulme house noted. Also shows much more forest round Berenty reserve and no forest connection between Malaza and Ankoba. Not sure of date probably from 1950 air photo survey
    - road map of Tananarive, 1960; map (Box 14, Folder 16)
      A very much smaller town!
    - notes on Ampanity mohair rug weaving Author: Alison Jolly Location:, 1963; notes (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - 1: 100,000 maps of Maroansetra and Masoala, 1958; map (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - 1: 100,000 maps of Ankarafantsika area, 1958; map (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - large scale relief map of Madagascar and Comoros, 1957; map (Box 15, Folder 1)
      Legend cut off.
    - The tradition of home ranges among the lemurs of Berenty Reserve Author: Alison Jolly Location:, 1975; abstract (Box 15, Folder 2)
      importance of long-term studies and collaboration.
    - letter to Richard Author: Alison Jolly, May-17; copy of letter (Box 15, Folder 2)
      rained in on the Masoata
    - letter to Richard Author: Alison Jolly, 29-May-75; copy of letter (Box 15, Folder 2)
      plans for zoo guest house and map for kids of sites to visit for book
    - letter to Richard Author: Alison Jolly, 5-Jun-75; original letter (Box 15, Folder 2)
      Tulear Reef
    - letters to AMK Author: AJ, 1975; typed letters (Box 15, Folder 2)
      Angarokely forest station plateau forest. Egbert Leigh, Jean-Prospere Abraham, Russ Kinne, Skip Barbour, outline of plateu chapter. The Frog-Lady's picnic: Mpanjakatompko forest with Mme Margerite Razare-helisoa
    - letters from Margaretta and Susan Author: SJ and MJ Location:, 1975; original letters (Box 15, Folder 2)
      with accounts of animals in the zoo and airplane
    - World like our own draft, chapter 3 Author: Alison Jolly Location:, 1975; typed draft (Box 15, Folder 2)
      The sacred lemurs of Laudohalika
    - World like our own - rough drafts Author: Alison Jolly Location:, 1975; typed drafts (Box 15, Folder 2)
      Much cut later to take out personal parts. Originally encouraged by knopf editor to write it as a diary. After refusals by knopf and others, on the grounds that 'no one ever heard of Madagascar so not worth publishing' final version taken by Yale University Press.
    - handwritten notes for A World like our own Author: Alison Jolly Location:, 1975; notebooks (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - original copy of letters from Madagascar November 19 1962 - February 8th 1963 Author: AJ Madagascar, 1962-3; original letters, typed (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - letters from Madagascar Author: Alison Jolly Madagascar, Feb 15 - June 1963; original letters, typed (Box 15, Folder 4)
      including engagement to Richard
    - Malagasy stamps Location: Madagascar, 1963; stamps (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - observations on Galago Crassicaudadus Author: Alison Jolly Location:, 1966; typed notes (Box 15, Folder 4)
      sent (with the galago colony) to Dr. E.G.F. Sauer in Florida. July 1966, Lusaka. Ethogram of G. Crassicaudatus
    - letter from Jeffrey Smith to John and Vina Buettner-Janusch Author: Jeffrey Smith Location:, 1963; original letter, typed (Box 15, Folder 4)
      The flight home with Preston, lemurs and minus one giant chameleon
    - Lemur Island' draft article Author: Alison Jolly, 1963-64; draft article, typed (Box 15, Folder 4)
      draft article for National Geographic, forestalled since editor Louis Marsden wnted to do his own! Account of Fenistina's difficult birth.
    - sex ratio and dominance in social lemurs Author: Alison Jolly Location:, 1964; paper (Box 15, Folder 5)
      paper presented in Nairobi 1964 July or August, Academy of Sciences. I month pregnant with MJ but didn't know it.
    - Alice Lenshina Zambian prophetess, 1965; newspaper cutting, envelope and report (Box 15, Folder 5)
      report of the commission of inquiry into the former lumpa church
    - The trip to Barotseland with MJ Author: Alison Jolly Location: Lusaka, March 23 1965; typed notes (Box 15, Folder 5)
      a full account of negotiations for copper royalties at Zambia's independence.
    - A weekend in the Congo Author: Alison Jolly, 1966; typed notes (Box 15, Folder 5)
      trip to Elizabethville in Katanoa with 1 year old MJ and an incipient coup.
    - letter to AMK and MGB on Lusaka housing Author: Alison Jolly Location:, 8-Jun-66; original letter, typed (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - postcard from Robert Oakeshott Author: Robert Oakeshott Location: Lusaka, 1965; postcard (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Book outline on Zambia with Robert Oakshott, 1965-6; handwritten notes (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - notes on Lusaka housing and density for Robert Oakshott Location: Lusaka, 1965-6; typed notes (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - summary notes Galago crassicaulatus Author: Alison Jolly Location: Lusaka, 1965; notebook (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Children's isolation ward, Lusaka hospital Author: Alison Jolly Location: Lusaka, 1966; typed notes (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - attempts to teach Margaretta aged 1, to 'read' with silly fashionable card method. Author: AJ Lusaka, 1966; handwritten notes (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - poem written at the end of Charles Remington's evolution course incorporating all buzzwords Author: Alison Jolly Yale, 1960; handwritten notes (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - story of Betty Polonista and should women have education Author: Alison Jolly Location:, 1960; handwritten story (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - The Idea of Objects' Author: Alison Jolly Yale, 1960; paper (Box 15, Folder 6)
      paper written for G.E. Hutchinson and for psychology course with reference to Whitehead and Piaget
    - letter to AMK about 'The Idea of an Object' Author: Alison Jolly Location: Yale, 1959; handwritten letter (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Malagasy school books Location: Madagascar, 1963; school books (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Mr Alanules Monster or The Ideal Machine Author: Alison Jolly Location: Cornell, 1958; typed play script (Box 15, Folder 8)
      short play for Willard Strait competition which didn't win.
    - creative writings Author: Alison Jolly Cornell and high school, 1952-58; typed poems and stories (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - letter from Catherine White re: 'Pilgrimage to Chartres', 1957; typed letter and story (Box 15, Folder 8)
      The New Yorker letter expressing reasons for publishing fictional and non-fictional accounts.
    - Prolegomena to the study of The Descent of Man: a pre-anniversay volume Author: A.Bishop and G.E. Hutchinson, paper (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Term paper for Ithaca habitats for Lamont Cole's ecology course - zoology 404 Author: A. Bishop Cornell, 1956; black bound term paper (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - lemur notebooks Author: AJ Madagascar, 1962-64; small notebooks (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - notebooks and postcard Author: Alison Jolly Madagascar, 1975; notebooks and postcard (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - summary notes L. catta mating season Author: Alison Jolly Location: Madagascar, 1964; notebook (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - summary notebook Author: Alison Jolly Berenty, 1970; notebook (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Berenty and first field trips Author: Alison Jolly Berenty, 1962; notebooks (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Nairobi sykes monkeys Author: Alison Jolly Nairobi, 1971; notebooks (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - MGB's letters, other correspondence, and pamphlets, originals and duplicates (Box 16, Folder 1-7)
      Cornell to check.
    - Correspondence about Alison's wedding plans, 1960s; letters (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - letters from Lusaka, 1970; letters (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Madagascar letters Author: Alison Jolly, 1962-63; letters (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Madagascar stamps, 1962-63; stamps (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Menus, de Grasse Location: Greece, 1951; menus (Box 19, Folder 11)
      My parents wanted me to experience Europe as they had known it. They saw that almost all transatlantic crossings would soon be by plane. They chose to cross first class on the slowest French line ship (10 days to Portsmouth) the de Grasse, known for superb cuisine to make up for lack of speed. I longed to be in 3rd class where young people seemed to have fun. At least I got to dance with Alec Waugh (Evelyn's brother) at the captain's dinner though he eventually reconciled on asking my age. I was 14.
    - Letters and documents, unsorted, 1990s; letters and diaries (Box 19, Folder 12-14)
    - Letters and documents, unsorted, 1990s; letters and diaries (Box 21, Folder 1-2)
    - Berenty data and field notes Author: Alison Jolly Berenty, 1983-84; includes statistical data and field notes (Box 22, Folder 1-14)
      items not listed, Cornell to check
    - Berenty data and field notes Author: Alison Jolly Berenty, 1989-91; includes mainly statistical data (Box 23, Folder 1-10)
    - Historic Maps of Madagascar Location: Madagascar, maps (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Colin Radford Author: Colin Radford Berenty, Fort Dauphin, 2003; photos and letter (Box 23, Folder 12)
      including ship wrecks and moon rise
    - infant galago Crassicaulatus, Darwin and friends Author: John BJ and Stephen Nash, two prints (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Lemur B originals, photos (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Lemur B originals, photos (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - French lemur comics, "Leapin' Lemurs", Copies of National Geographuc (Oct. 1967, Feb. 1987, Aug. 1988) (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Madagascar Maps (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Book plates (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Ny Tsididy Bitika, lemur cards, and wallet, My Aiay Ako (Box 23, Folder 15)
- Series IV. Photographs
  - Ranomafany with negatives (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Jean de Heaulme (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Alison Jolly as a child, 1930s-1950s (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Alison Jolly on Mauretania, 1956 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Alison Jolly, Baldwin School, 1954 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Portrait by Louise Baldwin (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Chimp photos and letter from Sue Savage (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Alison Jolly as a child (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Alison Jolly as a child (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - AJ's children (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - AJ's passport (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Digital pictures (Box 21, Folder 6-7)
  - Madagascar, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Pres. Ravelomanana and Unicef, 2002 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Margaretta's photo album gift to Alison (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Madagascar (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Unidentified photos (Box 21, Folder 9-10)
  - UNICEF, 1984 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Madagascar slides (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - AJ's wedding album (Box 16)
  - Photo album of lemurs (Box 21)
  - Kappa Alpha Theta group photo, 1957 (Box 25)
  - Alison Jolly with AMK, taken by Louise Boyle, 1937 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Family photos and letters (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - photo album (Box 17)
- Series V. Audio-visual Material
  - Only in Maagascar Author: Grace Pease Mad, 2005; CD-2613 (Box 21)
    Grace Pease is slightly disabled girl who raises money and effort for David Krause's NGO. Parents are film-makers. Good indri footage
  - Four Marks Primary Location: Westminster, 2007; V-9024 (Box 21)
    Alison Jolly reading Ako Book to school class
  - Lemur Island ep.1 Author: Discovery Channel Berenty, 2008; DVD-1552 (Box 21)
    episode to edit.
  - Lemur Island ep 10 Author: Discovery Channel Berenty, 2008; DVD-1565 (Box 22)
    Episode to edit
  - Fasimainty en Images Author: Rio Tinto Ft. Dauphin, DVD-1557 (Box 21)
    Rio propaganda about good things they do
  - Madagascar Island of Marvels Author: BBC AJ advised, DVD-1559 (Box 21)
  - Society, Natural Resources and Development in Mad. Author: Barry Ferguson, East Anglia AJ keynote, also many anthro crits of conservation policy, 2007; DVD-1556 (Box 21)
  - Ny Ako band, Malagasy music Author: Ny Ako band Location:, DVD-1558 (Box 21)
  - Lemur Street Location: Berenty, 2007; DVD-1566-1588 (Box 22)
    6 episodes, 16 DVDs
  - Young Impact Author: Lewes Railway Land Lewes, 2006; DVD-1553 (Box 21)
    AJ's main Lewes interest, also fund Hanta for Ambohimanga
  - Madagascar, A new vision Author: USAID, Andrew Young, Archipelago Films Location: Mad, 2003; DVD-1554 (Box 21)
    Ravelomanana's vision for conservation
  - Boky Tour? 2 discs, 2000; DVD-1550-1551 (Box 21)
  - African Voices, profile of Hanta Rasamimanana Author: CNN Location: Berenty, 2010; DVD-1542 (Box 21)
    "Madagascar's Lemur Lady"
  - Westdene Interview Author: Westdene school Brighto, 2011; DVD-1538 (Box 21)
    Junior reporters from Westdene Primary school, Brighton, interview Alison Jolly re Ako Project
  - Alison reading, Combe Rd School Author: Silveredge films Location: Brighton, DVD-1590-1592 (Box 22)
    Ako stories, Ako language teaching
  - Tandroy forests Author: Barry Ferguson Location:, DVD-1589 (Box 22)
    Tandroy school pack, World Bank deforestation, sacred forests
  - Lemur IDs Author: Radford Berenty, 2003; DVD-1539 (Box 21)
    Vet study to find bald lemur syndrom
  - Tandroy dancing and lemur sounds Author: Wendy Miles Location: Berenty, 2003; DVD-1560 (Box 21)
    Audio, vocalizatiions
  - Expedition Presentation Author: Wendy Miles Location: Berenty, 2003; DVD-1563 (Box 21)
  - Berenty Map Author: George Williams Berenty, DVD-1537 (Box 21)
    Original base map program for research
  - Plantes Médicinales de Madagascar Author: Pierre Boiteau and Lucile Allorge Location: Mad., DVD-1549 (Box 21)
    Father daughter collaboration
  - Ako school reading Author: Four Marks School Location: Winchester, DVD-1562 (Box 21)
  - Indri Files singing Author: Viviana Sorrentino Location: Andasibe, DVD-1543 (Box 21)
    Original inspiration for Ako book "No-Song the Indri"
  - Scheme of regional devel of Anosy Author: QMM Location:, 2004; DVD-1564 (Box 21)
  - Railway Land Environmental Learning Author: John Parry Location:, DVD-1593 (Box 31)
  - Marketplace Africa. Hanta? Author: CNN Location:, 2010; DVD-1546 (Box 21)
  - Attenborough and the Giant Egg Author: BBC Location:, DVD-1547 (Box 21)
  - USAID ecoregional alliance Author: USAID Anosy, 2004; DVD-1548 (Box 21)
    USAID, QMM, Lisa Gaylord
  - QMM 07 Author: Rio Tinto, 2007; DVD-1555 (Box 21)
  - QMM 05 Author: Rio Tinto Fort Dauphin, 2005; DVD-1544 (Box 21)
  - Lewes Flood Plans, 2009; DVD-1540 (Box 21)
  - Nouvelle Animation Author: Efraima Rakotosamimanan Location:, DVD-1545 (Box 21)
    Cartoons by Mme Berthe's son, whom I helped to publish
  - College La Clairefontaine, QMM Author: Rio Tinto Fort Dauphin, DVD-1541 (Box 21)
    School founded by QMM, as only way to attract skilled cadres from Tana
  - Seven Wonders of the World Author: Alison Jolly, BBC Location:, 1997; DVD-1561 (Box 21)
  - Jean de Heaulme, prison Author: Alison Jolly Location: Berenty, 2000; tr-10822 (Box 21)